in the celebrated example of prisoner's
在囚犯的著名例子中
dilemma we have this general scheme
困境，我们有这个总体方案
where the two prisoners can either
两个囚犯可以
cooperate or not defect as is called if
合作或不存在缺陷
they both cooperate they get some payoff
他们俩都合作，他们得到了一些回报
a-and if they both defect they get a
-如果他们俩都叛逆，他们会得到一个
different payoff D where a is greater
a较大时的不同收益D
than D however if they miss coordinate
比D但是如果他们错过坐标
and one of them cooperates and the other
其中一个合作，另一个
defects then the cooperator gets the
缺陷，然后合作者得到
lowest possible payoff and the defector
最低的回报和叛逃者
gets the largest possible path and
得到最大可能的路径
that's true symmetrically here as well
在这里对称也是如此
and this a very well-known example that
这是一个非常著名的例子
has a rather counterintuitive
有点违反直觉
paradoxical properties most games are
大多数游戏的悖论性质
not as conceptually confusing here's an
没有概念上的混乱，这是
example that conceptually very clear and
这个例子在概念上非常清楚，
these are gains of pure competition the
这些都是纯竞争的收益
situation here is limited to two players
这种情况仅限于两名球员
where one players payoff is exactly the
一个玩家的收益正好是
complement of another players payoff so
补充另一个玩家的收益，所以
they always sum to some constant C often
他们经常总和一些常数C
that concept is that we use zero and we
这个概念是我们使用零，我们
call them for that reason zero-sum games
称他们为零和游戏
as opposed to constant sum games
与固定和博弈相反
and since they do sum to zero or to
由于它们的总和为零或
constant we only need to remember one
不变，我们只需要记住一个
number the path to one of the players
编号玩家之一的路径
and we can infer the payoff to the other
我们可以推断其他人的收益
player from that here's the most simple
玩家从这里最简单
version of it this is a games of
它的版本是
matching pennies so you and I each need
匹配便士，所以您和我都需要
to pick either heads or tail for the for
为之挑选头或尾
the coin if we pick the same side either
如果我们选择同一面的话
heads or tails I win which means that I
头或尾我赢了，这意味着我
get a payoff of 1 and U of minus 1 if we
如果我们得到1的收益和-1的U
miss coordinate and so I pick heads and
想念坐标，所以我挑了头
you tailed or the other way around then
你拖尾或反过来
you win a very straightforward game of
您会赢得一个非常简单的游戏
pure competition
纯竞争
here's another word our very well-known
这是我们非常知名的另一个词
similar games with three actions both of
具有三个动作的相似游戏
us and that's the game of rock papers
我们就是摇滚游戏
and scissors
和剪刀
also known as Rochambeau and so if we
也被称为Rochambeau，所以如果我们
pick the same action then it's a draw
选择相同的动作然后平局
and otherwise there are rules for who
否则有谁的规则
wins for example if I pick Rock and you
例如，如果我选择Rock而您获胜
paper the new one if I picked Rock and
如果我选择了Rock，
use scissors then I win and so on again
用剪刀，然后我赢了，依此类推
the payoffs in both cases sum to zero
两种情况下的收益总和为零
this parenthetically this very simple
这很简单
children game actually has an annual
儿童游戏实际上每年都有
competition that carries a non-trivial
不平凡的竞争
prize of $10,000 and it's actually a
奖金$ 10,000，实际上是
sobering thought
清醒的思想
that when we look at this trivial game
当我们看这个琐碎的游戏时
then perhaps check a little bit if we
然后也许检查一下
actually participate in this competition
参加比赛
we'd actually think hard about how to
我们实际上会认真思考如何
play it is the other extreme of games of
玩是游戏的另一极端
pure coordination or pure cooperation in
纯粹的协调或纯粹的合作
this case all agents have exactly the
在这种情况下，所有代理商都有
same interest in other words their
换句话说，他们的兴趣相同
payoffs for every action vector that
每个动作向量的收益
they take is the same and so the utility
他们采取的是相同的，所以实用程序
for play I is always the same of utility
对于玩游戏，我永远都是相同的工具
for pair J for every action sequence
对于J对每个动作序列
that they choose and so again we here -
他们选择，所以我们再次在这里-
we only need to write in each cell of
我们只需要在
the matrix only one number because it's
矩阵只有一个数字，因为
common to all the players it drives home
它带回家的所有球员都是共同的
the perhaps the unfortunate term
也许是不幸的术语
noncorporeal game theory that describes
非物质博弈论
this dominant strand of game theory
博弈论的主导
we're discussing for now it's the name
我们现在正在讨论的是名字
would suggest that these are games for
会建议这些是
that describe situations that are
描述情况
inherent inherently conflictual but as
内在固有的冲突，但作为
we see they apply also to games in which
我们看到它们也适用于其中
the interests of the players coincide so
玩家的利益是一致的
here's a here's a game that
这是一个游戏
describes the purely court cooperative
描述纯粹的法院合作社
situation you and I walk each other
你和我互相走动的情况
towards each other on the sidewalk we
在人行道上彼此接近
can each decide whether to go to our
每个人都可以决定是否去我们的
respective lay lifts our respective
各自的升降机
right and if we pick the same side then
对，如果我们选择同一边，那么
all is good we avoid a collision if we
一切都很好，如果我们避免碰撞
don't then the then we do collide and
然后，那么我们就发生了碰撞，
that's equally bad for both of us of
这对我们两个人都同样有害
course in general gains will be neither
当然，总的收益不会
purely cooperative nor purely
纯粹合作也不是纯粹
conflictual and here's a game that
冲突，这是一个游戏
exemplifies that this is a game that
举例说明这是一款
called battle of the sexes imagine a
所谓的性别之战想象
husband and a wife we want to go out to
丈夫和妻子，我们想出去
a movie there are two movies they could
电影可以有两部电影
choose from let's say Battle of
从说“战役”中选择
Armageddon and flower child the one a
大决战和花童一个
violent war movie and the other is a is
暴力战争电影，另一个是
a romantic comedy above all they want to
他们想要的浪漫喜剧
go together to the movie if they go to
一起去看电影，如果他们去
different movies then they are equally
不同的电影，他们都是一样的
unhappy so they want to go to the same
不开心，所以他们想去同一个
movie but they have conflicting
电影，但他们有冲突
preferences the wife clearly would
妻子的喜好显然会
prefer to go to battle of Armageddon and
宁愿去参加世界末日之战，
husband romantic as he is would like to
丈夫浪漫，因为他想
go to flower child
去花童
so both cooperation and competition in
因此，在
this game
这个游戏